let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is milt?",
    answer: "The sperm of a male broodstock",
    options: [
      "A juvenile",
      "The sperm of a male broodstock",
      "Oocytes",
      "Fisheries"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The type of mouth possessed by most catfish is?",
    answer: "Inferior",
    options: [
      "Terminal",
      "Protrusible",
      "Superior",
      "Inferior"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "A gravid fish is a fish that?",
    answer: "Has a lot of eggs",
    options: [
      "Has a lot of eggs",
      "Has spawned already",
      "retarded growth",
      "Fattening"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "One the following is not an importance of fish/fisheries",
    answer: "Apt culture",
    options: [
      "Aesthetics",
      "Apt culture",
      "Medicine",
      "Food"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Another name for fish tail is",
    answer: "Caudal fin",
    options: [
      "Dorsal fin",
      "Pectoral fin",
      "Caudal fin",
      "Pelvic fin"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What is the order after hatching?",
    answer: "Fries-fingerlings-juveniles-broodstock",
    options: [
      "Fries-fingerlings-juveniles-broodstock",
      "Fingerlings-fries-juveniles-broodstocks",
      "Broodstocks-fries-fingerlings-juveniles",
      "None of the aforementioned"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Another name for raceway is?",
    answer: "Flow-Through System",
    options: [
      "Flow-Through System",
      "Tanks",
      "Reservoir",
      "Spillway"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The channel constructed along an embankment aimed at taking excess water away from the pond is called?",
    answer: "Spillway",
    options: [
      "dyke",
      "Levee",
      "Monk",
      "Spillway"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 9,
    question: "_______is the administration of drugs to fish, not for corrective reasons but for preservative reasons",
    answer: "Prophylaxis",
    options: [
      "Prophylaxis",
      "Antemin",
      "Cure",
      "Diagnosis"
    ]
  },
 {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Anorexia means?",
    answer: "Severe loss of appetite",
    options: [
      "Diagnosis",
      "Severe loss of appetite",
      "Constipation",
      "Necrosis"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 11,
    question: "In fish, lack of vitamin  C causes__________",
    answer: "Broken back disease",
    options: [
      "Scurvy",
      "Lipoid Liver Degeneration",
      "Broken back disease",
      "Di-epigenetics"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 12,
    question: "Oxygen starvation leads to a condition called?",
    answer: "Anorexia",
    options: [
      "Anorexia",
      "Necrosis",
      "Anoxia",
      "Diaphragm daialysis"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 13,
    question: "Oyster belongs to the class?",
    answer: "Mollusca",
    options: [
      "Pisces",
      "Mollusca",
      "Reptila",
      "Coelenterata"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 14,
    question: "An exmaple of bony fish is _____",
    answer: "Tilapia",
    options: [
      "Ray",
      "Skate",
      "Tilapia",
      "Whale"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 15,
    question: "______ is the reproduction that allows eggs to fertilize and develop in the female fish without direct nourishment from the mother",
    answer: "Ovoviviparity",
    options: [
      "Ovoviviparity",
      "Oviparity",
      "Viviparity",
      "Ovuliparity"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which of the following is against fishing regulations?",
    answer: "Over fishing",
    options: [
      "Adequate technical know-how",
      "Government policy",
      "Adequate government support",
      "Over fishing"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 17,
    question: "The following are sources of protein in fish feed EXCEPT",
    answer: "Wheat",
    options: [
      "Soya beans",
      "Groundnut cake",
      "Wheat",
      "Fish meal"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 18,
    question: "The eggs associated with marine fishes are called?",
    answer: "Pelagic eggs",
    options: [
      "Pelagic eggs",
      "Oology",
      "Demersal eggs",
      "Salt eggs"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 19,
    question: "Tilapia spp belongs to the family",
    answer: "Cichlidae",
    options: [
      "Claridae",
      "Bagridae",
      "Mormridae",
      "Cichlidae"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 20,
    question: "______ is the act of introducing water into the Pond",
    answer: "Impoundment",
    options: [
      "Allotment",
      "Impoundment",
      "Embankment",
      "Copulation"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 21,
    question: " ______ is a tool to harvest fish for commercial purpose",
    answer: "Fish Trawler",
    options: [
      "Basket",
      "Capture Gillnet",
      "Scoop net",
      "Fish Trawler"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 22,
    question: "The introduction of fish into a fish pond is called?",
    answer: "Stocking",
    options: [
      "Imputing",
      "Spawning",
      "Stocking",
      "Feeding"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 23,
    question: "Zooplankton and phytoplankton are example of ____",
    answer: "Natural feed",
    options: [
      "Fish diet",
      "Natural feed",
      "Artificial feed",
      "Basal"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 24,
    question: "The following are feeding methods used in fish EXCEPT _____",
    answer: "Ginning De'Feed",
    options: [
      "Automated Feeding",
      "Broadcasting Feeding",
      "Spot Feeding",
      "Ginning De'Feed"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 25,
    question: "The term fish gear refers to____",
    answer: "The equipment used for harvesting fish",
    options: [
      "The equipment used for harvesting fish",
      "Fish gear box",
      "Tool used in processing fish",
      "Vessels used for transporting fish"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 26,
    question: "Fish are poikilothermic and they belong to the family called?",
    answer: "Pisces",
    options: [
      "Crustaceans",
      "Pisces",
      "Reptila",
      "Mollusca"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 27,
    question: "An example of common  culturable fish species in Nigeria is _____",
    answer: "Tilapia",
    options: [
      "Tilapia",
      "Sardine",
      "Mackerel",
      "Shark"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 28,
    question: "The preservation of fish that does not change its form is known as?",
    answer: "Freezing",
    options: [
      "Prickling",
      "Canning",
      "Smoking",
      "Freezing"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 29,
    question: "The following factors are considered in selecting brood stock for artificial breeding I. swollen genital papilla II. Reddish genital papilla III. Protruding abdomen in female",
    answer: "I, II & III",
    options: [
      "I, II & III",
      "II & III only",
      "I & III only",
      "I only"
    ]
  },
{
    numb: 30,
    question: "The importance  of monk is that it _____",
    answer: "controls the level of pond water",
    options: [
      "Prays for fish",
      "Facilitate spawning",
      "Controls the level of pond water",
      "Controls zooplankton growth"
    ]
  },
];
